Hi.
My name is Dr. Art Bowler.
And I'm a psychologist in Manhattan, New York City, where I have my own private practice.
In this clip I'm going to talk about how to tell if you have low self esteem.
Low self esteem or a low feeling about oneself is unfortunately very common.
But fortunately it's very fixable.
When one has low self esteem, the way you can tell is look in the mirror.
How do you feel about yourself?
What do you see?
Do you see the positive parts of your personality or do you notice the negative?
Are you always focused on the positive aspects of your physical self instead of the negative?
If so you have high self esteem.
Low self esteem tends to bring us down and there's a set of thoughts or cognitions that tend to go with low self esteem.
Such as I am unlove, unlovable and no one will like me.
By doing cognitive therapy and working on those thoughts, we can help our clients to feel better about themselves by gaining a more accurate appraisal of themselves, their situation and their environment.
It's really important to notice if you have low self esteem because then you can do something about it.
This is Dr. Art Bowler and this has been how to tell if you have low self esteem.